<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30403658</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>11</Month>            <Day>07</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Electronic">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1643-3750</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>24</Volume>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Nov</Month>                        <Day>07</Day>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Medical science monitor : international medical journal of experimental and clinical research</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Med. Sci. Monit.</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>Correlation of Expression Levels of Micro Ribonucleic Ccid-10b (miR-10b) and Micro Ribonucleic Acid-181b (miR-181b) with Gastric Cancer and Its Diagnostic Significance.</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>7988-7995</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12659/MSM.910809</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>BACKGROUND The aim of this study was to explore the expression levels of micro ribonucleic acid-10b (miR-10b) and micro ribonucleic acid-181b (miR-181b) in gastric cancer tissues, as well as their application value in clinical diagnosis and treatment. MATERIAL AND METHODS A total of 120 patients with gastric cancer who were diagnosed and treated in the Department of Gastroenterology of our hospital were enrolled in this study. The gastric cancer tissues and paracancerous tissues were collected for measuring the expression of miR-10b and miR-181b by in situ hybridization and reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR). The 5-year survival rate was also analyzed. RESULTS The expressions of miR-10b and miR-181b in gastric cancer tissues were both upregulated and were significantly higher than those in the paracancerous tissues (p&lt;0.05). In addition, the expressions of miR-10b and miR-181b in gastric cancer tissues were correlated with tumor size, degree of pathological differentiation, depth of infiltration, tumor node metastasis (TNM) staging, and lymph node metastasis, as well as local lymph node and distant metastasis (p&lt;0.05). For patients in stage II and III, the expressions of miR-10b and miR-181b were significantly correlated with the 5-year survival rate. CONCLUSIONS The high expressions of miR-10b and miR-181b are significantly correlated with poor prognosis in stage II and III patients with gastric cancer, suggesting that their expressions might be criteria for evaluating the prognosis of gastric cancer.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Gao</LastName>                    <ForeName>Ying</ForeName>                    <Initials>Y</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Inspection, Weifang People's Hospital, Weifang, Shandong, China (mainland).</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Xu</LastName>                    <ForeName>Zhicai</ForeName>                    <Initials>Z</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Breast Surgery, Weifang People's Hospital, Weifang, Shandong, China (mainland).</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Yuan</LastName>                    <ForeName>Fei</ForeName>                    <Initials>F</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Weifang People's Hospital, Weifang, Shandong, China (mainland).</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Li</LastName>                    <ForeName>Minglei</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Weifang People's Hospital, Weifang, Shandong, China (mainland).</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>07</Day>            </ArticleDate>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>United States</Country>            <MedlineTA>Med Sci Monit</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>9609063</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>1234-1010</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>8</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>8</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>8</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30403658</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="pii">910809</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12659/MSM.910809</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>