<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30387470</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>11</Month>            <Day>02</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0028-2715</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">                    <Volume>56</Volume>                    <Issue>212</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <MedlineDate>2018 Jul-Aug</MedlineDate>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>JNMA; journal of the Nepal Medical Association</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>JNMA J Nepal Med Assoc</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>Ultrasonographic Elasticity Contrast Index of Palpable Breast Lumps.</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>787-790</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Elastrography used in addition to grey scale sonography increases its specificity. Elasticity contrast index (ECI) is based on strain elastrography and being a quantitative parameter, maybe more easy to obtain and reproducible while researches has been done in ECI in thyroid lesions, this is the first study, to the best of our knowledge to evaluate in breast lesions. This study was done to evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of Elasticity Contrast Index (ECI) in differentiating benign from malignant lesions of breast and to determine its cutoff value.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a descriptive cross-sectional study done at tertiary health care centre, which involved retrospective evaluation of data collected from September 2016 to March 2017. Conventional sonography was done followed by elastography on commercially available ultrasound machine. ECI was calculated in thyroid protocol available in the unit. Histopathological diagnosis was obtained for all the lesions and taken as gold standard.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 89 breast lumps were evaluated, of which was 61 (69.3%) were benign and 27 (30.7%) malignant on histopathology. Independent t test revealed the average ECI value of benign lesions was 2.48 and malignant 5.1. Receiver operating curve showed ECI value of 3.25 as the cutoff, above which the lesions were malignant.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">ECI is a quantitative elastography technique which can be easily used as an adjunct during breast sonography and can increase its specificity for diagnosing a lesion as malignant. This could reduce the number of false positive biopsies.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Jha</LastName>                    <ForeName>Anamika</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Radiology &amp; Imaging, Institute of Medicine, Tribhuvan University Teaching Hospital, Maharajgunj, Kathmandu, Nepal.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Nepal</Country>            <MedlineTA>JNMA J Nepal Med Assoc</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>0045233</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0028-2715</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer; Elastography; Strain Elastography; Ultrasonography.</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>3</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>6</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>6</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30387470</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>