<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30365854</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>10</Month>            <Day>26</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1678-4561</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>23</Volume>                    <Issue>10</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Oct</Month>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Ciencia &amp; saude coletiva</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Cien Saude Colet</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[The use of virtual communities in the support to patients with breast cancer].</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>3347-3356</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1413-81232018001003347</ELocationID>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1590/1413-812320182310.14612018</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>Thinking about virtual communities as a space for interaction and the sharing of experiences, especially among individuals affected by chronic diseases, the scope of this study was to analyze the role and nature of support offered by virtual communities to breast cancer patients. It is a descriptive study with a qualitative approach. For data collection, the Netvizz application was used extracting data from the first five Facebook open breast cancer groups in the year 2016. There were 2921 posts, totaling 1722 comments. For data analysis a word cloud was created through WordArt, and the most recurrent words were discussed in cross-sectional categories: I, confessional, vs. you, interactional; therapeutic process, religiosity and the &quot;Intervention Window.&quot; The results show that the support offered in these spaces occurs especially in the informational and emotional spheres, ranging from the diagnosis phase to the control of the disease. The understanding of the significance of the information shared in the virtual communities by women with breast cancer can contribute to the practice of care that is not restricted to the biological and technical approaches, but rather a more comprehensive and effective approach to holistic care.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Melo</LastName>                    <ForeName>Myllena Cândida de</ForeName>                    <Initials>MC</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Câncer. R. Equador 831, Santo Cristo. 20220-410 Rio de Janeiro RJ Brasil. myllena.melo@inca.gov.br.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Vasconcellos-Silva</LastName>                    <ForeName>Paulo Roberto</ForeName>                    <Initials>PR</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Câncer. R. Equador 831, Santo Cristo. 20220-410 Rio de Janeiro RJ Brasil. myllena.melo@inca.gov.br.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>por</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Uso de comunidades virtuais no suporte a portadoras de câncer de mama.</VernacularTitle>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Brazil</Country>            <MedlineTA>Cien Saude Colet</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>9713483</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>1413-8123</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="por">            <AbstractText>Pensando nas comunidades virtuais como espaço de interação e compartilhamento de experiências, principalmente entre indivíduos acometidos por doenças crônicas, objetivamos com este estudo, analisar o papel e natureza de suporte oferecido pelas comunidades virtuais às portadoras de câncer de mama. Estudo descritivo com abordagem qualitativa. Para coleta de dados foi utilizado o aplicativo Netvizz, extraindo dados dos cinco primeiros grupos abertos de câncer de mama do Facebook, no ano de 2016. Foram encontradas 2921 postagens, totalizando 1722 comentários. Para análise dos dados foi criada uma nuvem de palavras através do WordArt, e as palavras mais recorrentes foram discutidas em categorias transversais: Eu Confessional X Você Interacional; processo terapêutico, religiosidade e “Arco de Intervenções”. Constatamos, pelos resultados, que o suporte oferecido nestes espaços se dá especialmente nas esferas informacional e emocional, indo desde a fase de diagnóstico até o controle da doença. A compreensão das significações das informações partilhadas nas comunidades virtuais por mulheres com câncer de mama pode contribuir para a realização de práticas de cuidado que não se restrinjam às abordagens de cunho biológico e tecnicista, mas sim numa assistência holística, integral e efetiva.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>01</Month>                <Day>31</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>05</Month>                <Day>30</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30365854</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1413-81232018001003347</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1413-812320182310.14612018</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>