<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30360602</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>10</Month>            <Day>26</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Electronic">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2476-762X</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>19</Volume>                    <Issue>10</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Oct</Month>                        <Day>26</Day>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Asian Pacific journal of cancer prevention : APJCP</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Asian Pac. J. Cancer Prev.</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>Mediating Factors in Early Diagnosis of Breast Cancer: from Initial Changes in Health to Breast Cancer Detection</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>2751-2755</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>Background: Breast cancer is one of the most frequently occurring cancers in women throughout the world. InIran, according to available reports, 70% of patients with breast cancer are detected at the advanced stages of thedisease. Materials and Methods: This study is of descriptive-analytic cross-sectional type.160 female patients wasselected. The data in this study was collected via face to face interview using a questionnaire based on the Anderson’sdelay model. Data were analyzed using SPSS 22 and the significance level was considered to be 0.05. Results: Theresults showed that presence of mass was the first symptom in many of women, i.e., 76 cases (47.5%). not only thepresence of mass in the breast, but also any other symptom, hadn’t been taken as a serious problem initially by women.Non-improvement of the symptoms and exacerbation of the symptoms was considered as a symptom of illness bypatients. After considering the changes as the symptoms of illness, patients had tried to treat the disease through differentmethods of self-treatment. The failure of the self-treatment in controlling the symptoms, had directed the patientstoward seeking for medical services. Out of 160 patients, 49 patients (39.6%) changed the time of their appointmentwith doctor. 110 cases (68%) out of 160 patients, rather than initiating relevant diagnostic procedure related to thedisease, had received non-specific and non-related therapeutic measures. Conclusion: Pondering on the results yieldsthat patient-related delays, resulting from their lack of awareness of the disease, cultural factors, and fear, can onlyplay an important role in postponement of visiting a physician, but in the diagnosis of disease it is the inability ofgeneral practitioners in performing differential diagnoses, and making request for related diagnostic measures whichcan significantly increase the lag time until the onset of the main treatment.</AbstractText>                <CopyrightInformation>Creative Commons Attribution License</CopyrightInformation>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Fouladi</LastName>                    <ForeName>Nasrin</ForeName>                    <Initials>N</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Community Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Ardabil University of Medical Sciences, Ardabil, Iran.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Social Determinants of Health Research Center, Ardabil University of Medical Sciences, Ardabil, Iran. Email: n.fouladi@arums.ac.ir</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Pourfarzi</LastName>                    <ForeName>Farhad</ForeName>                    <Initials>F</Initials>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Daneshian</LastName>                    <ForeName>Aida</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Alimohammadi</LastName>                    <ForeName>Sara</ForeName>                    <Initials>S</Initials>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>26</Day>            </ArticleDate>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Thailand</Country>            <MedlineTA>Asian Pac J Cancer Prev</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>101130625</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>1513-7368</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">delay</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Anderson model</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>27</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30360602</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22034/APJCP.2018.19.10.2751</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>