<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30321007</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>11</Month>            <Day>13</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0035-3639</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">                    <Volume>39</Volume>                    <Issue>4</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <MedlineDate>2018</MedlineDate>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Revue medicale de Bruxelles</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Brux</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[Breast cancer screening : present situation and prospects].</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>406-409</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>Breast cancer screening is a public health challenge. Belgium has the worldwide highest age-standardized breast cancer incidence. It ranks third in terms of specific mortality. The causes are unclear and presumably multifactorial. Like most European countries, Belgium has set up a screening program since 2001. Despite coverage rates varying from one Region to another, the annual 2 % specific mortality decline (observed in the vast majority of European countries) is the same. The age-based screening programs recommended by the European Union are often debated for their questionable impact on mortality and on incidence of advanced tumors (stages II and beyond), and for the harms they may generates (over-diagnosis, false positives). A risk-stratified screening strategy considering other well-documented risk factors (family history, breast density, and genetic variants) could lead to better results while reducing the disadvantages. This hypothesis will be tested through the European My Personal Breast Screening (My PeBS) study, a multicenter randomized clinical trial involving 85,000 volunteers.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Burrion</LastName>                    <ForeName>J B</ForeName>                    <Initials>JB</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Prévention et Dépistage, Institut Jules Bordet, ULB.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>fre</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Dépistage du cancer du sein : actualité et perspectives.</VernacularTitle>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Belgium</Country>            <MedlineTA>Rev Med Brux</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>8003474</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0035-3639</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">            <AbstractText>Le dépistage du cancer du sein est un enjeu de santé publique. La Belgique possède le record mondial d’incidence du cancer du sein standardisée pour l’âge. Elle se classe en troisième position pour la mortalité spécifique. Les causes ne sont pas claires et vraisemblable- ment multifactorielles. Comme la plupart des pays européens, la Belgique a mis en place un programme de dépistage dès 2001. Malgré des taux de couvertures très différents selon les régions du pays, la baisse de mortalité spécifique de 2 % par an (observée dans la grande majorité des pays européens), est la même. La stratégie de dépistage basée sur l’âge comme seul facteur de risque est recommandée par l’Union européenne. Elle est souvent débattue pour son impact relatif sur la mortalité et quasi nul sur l’incidence des tumeurs avancées (stades II et au-delà) et pour les inconvénients qu’elle génère (surdiagnostics, faux positifs). Une stratégie de dépistage prenant en compte d’autres facteurs de risque aujourd’hui bien documentés (antécédents familiaux, densité mammaire, variants génétiques) pourrait conduire à de meilleurs résultats tout en diminuant les inconvénients. C’est ce que l’étude européenne My Personal Breast Screening (My PeBS) se propose de tester dans le cadre d’un essai clinique multicentrique randomisé portant sur 85.000 femmes volontaires.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer,</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risk-stratified screening</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Single nucleotide polymorphisms</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30321007</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>