<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30320989</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>11</Month>            <Day>13</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0035-3639</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">                    <Volume>39</Volume>                    <Issue>4</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <MedlineDate>2018</MedlineDate>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Revue medicale de Bruxelles</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Med Brux</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[Follow-up of breast cancer patients by general practioner].</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>280-286</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>In Belgium, breast cancer is the most frequent women's cancer accounting for to 35.3 % of the cases. In 2013, 10,778 newly diagnosed breast cancers have been reported in Belgium. Breast cancer has a relatively good prognosis with a 5 year overall survival of 88 %. Survival will be different regarding the subtype and stage at diagnosis. The review of the literature and the guidelines from ESMO and ASCO regarding the follow-up of patients with early breast cancer will be used as references. International guidelines recommend clinical visits (frequencies depending of the subtypes of breast cancer) with an annual mammography associated with an echography. MRI Imaging should be performed in &quot; at risk &quot; patients. A more extensive exploration should be proceede when a relapse is suspected during follow up. Indeed, studies have shown that intensive follow- up with several additional exams detect more recurrences without any impact on overall survival and lead to anxiety. The follow-up of patients treated for breast cancer has several objectives : - Detect a local recurrence or a second tumor ; - Diagnosis of a distant relapse ; - Detect side effects of treatment ; - Psycho-social impact of the disease and improve the quality of life.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Veys</LastName>                    <ForeName>I</ForeName>                    <Initials>I</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Service de Chirurgie mammo-pelvienne, Institut Jules Bordet, ULB.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>fre</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Suivi du cancer du sein par le médecin généraliste.</VernacularTitle>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Belgium</Country>            <MedlineTA>Rev Med Brux</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>8003474</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0035-3639</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="fre">            <AbstractText>En Belgique, le cancer du sein est le cancer le plus fréquent chez la femme (35,3 % des cas). En 2013, 10.778 nouveaux cancers du sein ont été répertoriés. Son pronostic est relativement bon, avec des taux de survie à cinq ans de 88 %. Il sera différent en fonction du type de cancer du sein et de son stade. La revue de la littérature et les recommandations actuelles de l’ESMO (European Society of Medical Oncology) et de l’ASCO (American Society of Clinical Oncology) concernant le suivi des patientes traitées pour un cancer du sein, seront prises comme références. Les recommandations internationales se limitent à des consultations cliniques (dont la fréquence peut varier selon les types de cancer du sein) associées à une mammographie de même qu’à une échographie mammaire annuelle tandis qu’une résonance magnétique nucléaire sera également réalisée chez les patientes à risque. Un bilan est à réaliser dans le cadre du suivi uniquement si une rechute est suspectée. En effet, de nombreuses études ont montré que la surveillance dite intensive est responsable certes de la découverte d’un plus grand nombre de rechutes, mais également d’une angoisse accrue chez les patientes et n’a pas d’impact favorable sur la survie sans progression ou sur la survie globale. La surveillance des patientes ayant été traitées pour un cancer du sein vise plusieurs objectifs : - Rechercher une récidive locale ou une deuxième tumeur ; - Diagnostiquer une récidive à distance ; - Détecter les possibles complications secondaires aux traitements adjuvants administrés ; - Évaluer le retentissement psycho-social de la maladie et améliorer la qualité de vie des patientes.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Follow up</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>16</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30320989</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>