<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30300431</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>10</Month>            <Day>09</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2083-8441</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>24</Volume>                    <Issue>2</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Pediatric endocrinology, diabetes, and metabolism</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Endocrinol Diabetes Metab</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[The impact of VDR gene polymorphisms on obesity, metabolic changes, bone mass disorders and neoplastic processes].</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>96-105</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18544/PEDM-24.02.0108</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>Vitamin D activity is controlled by its receptor (VDR) located in many cells of the body. The presence of VDR in numerous cellular pathways suggests its important role in the etiology and development of many diseases. Increased risk of obesity, metabolic disturbances, bone mass disturbances and neoplasia among certain VDR alleles has been proven. The importance of VDR in the etiopathology of obesity is associated with the occurrence of polymorphisms: Fok1, Bsm1, Apa1, Taq1. VDR expression in adipocytes plays a role in the regulation of energy metabolism and the induction of obesity. Vitamin D and VDR polymorphisms can participate in the development of many metabolic disorders. The VDR gene is one of the better researched genes among patients with type 1 diabetes. The action of vitamin D affects the proper functioning and development of the skeletal system. Vitamin D has an effect on bone remodeling through its receptor and its polymorphisms: Apa1, Bsm1, Taq1, Fok1 and Cdx2. The identification and diagnosis of VDR varieties gives the possibility of early detection of the risk of osteoporosis or individual predisposition to its development. There is a high variability in the results of individual VDR polymorphisms in relation to the occurrence of osteoporosis among various ethnic groups. The polymorphisms important in the neoplastic process include, among others, the polymorphism of Fok1, Bsm1, and Taq1. The association of VDR gene polymorphisms with the risk of breast cancer (Bsm1, Fok1), prostate cancer (Fok1) and malignant melanoma (Fok1) is indicated. The greatest importance in the prognosis is observed in patients with prostate cancer (F1), breast cancer (Bsm1, Taq1), malignant melanoma (Bsm1) and renal cell carcinoma (Taq1). It is important to identify, describe and correlate the occurrence of genetic polymorphisms of the VDR, which will allow early diagnosis or prevention of correlative entities correlated with them.</AbstractText>                <CopyrightInformation>© Polish Society for Pediatric Endocrinology and Diabetology.</CopyrightInformation>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Wysoczańska-Klaczyńska</LastName>                    <ForeName>Anna</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Wroclaw Medical University.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Ślęzak</LastName>                    <ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department and Clinic of Marrow Transplantation, Pediatric Oncology and Hematology, Wroclaw Medical University.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Hetman</LastName>                    <ForeName>Marta</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Student's Scientific Society, Deparment of Basic Medical Sciences, Wroclaw Medical University.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Barg</LastName>                    <ForeName>Ewa</ForeName>                    <Initials>E</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Basic Medical Sciences, Wroclaw Medical University.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>pol</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Wpływ polimorfizmów genu VDR na otyłość, zmiany metaboliczne, zaburzenia masy kostnej i procesy nowotworowe.</VernacularTitle>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Poland</Country>            <MedlineTA>Pediatr Endocrinol Diabetes Metab</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>101518750</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>2083-8441</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="pol">            <AbstractText>Aktywność witaminy D kontrolowana jest przez jej receptor (VDR) zlokalizowany w wielu komórkach organizmu. Obecność VDR w licznych szlakach komórkowych sugeruje jego istotną rolę w etiologii i rozwoju wielu chorób. Wykazano zwiększone ryzyko otyłości, zaburzeń metabolicznych i masy kostnej oraz nowotworzenia wśród pewnych alleli VDR. Znaczenie genu VDR w etiopatologii otyłości związane jest z występowaniem polimorfizmów: Fok1, Bsm1, Apa1, Taq1. Ekspresja VDR w adipocytach odgrywa rolę w regulacji metabolizmu energetycznego i indukowaniu wystąpienia otyłości. Witamina D i polimorfizmy VDR mogą uczestniczyć w rozwoju wielu schorzeń metabolicznych. Gen VDR jest jednym z lepiej zbadanych genów wśród pacjentów z cukrzycą typu 1. Działanie witaminy D wpływa na prawidłowe funkcjonowanie oraz rozwój układu kostnego. Efekt na przebudowę kości witamina D wywiera przez swój receptor i jego polimorfizmy: Apa1, Bsm1, Taq1, Fok1 i Cdx2. Identyfikacja i rozpoznanie odmian VDR daje możliwość wczesnego wykrycia ryzyka wystąpienia osteoporozy lub indywidualnej predyspozycji do jej rozwoju. Odnotowuje się dużą zmienność wyników badań poszczególnych polimorfizmów VDR w odniesieniu do występowania osteoporozy wśród różnych grup etnicznych. Do ważnych w procesie nowotworzenia polimorfizmów należą m.in.: polimorfizm Fok1, Bsm1 oraz Taq1. Wskazuje się związek polimorfizmów genu VDR z ryzykiem wystąpienia raka sutka (Bsm1, Fok1), raka prostaty (Fok1) i czerniaka złośliwego (Fok1). Największe znaczenie w rokowaniu obserwuje się u pacjentów z rakiem prostaty (Fok1), rakiem piersi (Bsm1, Taq1), czerniakiem złośliwym o (Bsm1) i rakiem nerkowokomórkowym (Taq1). Istotnym jest rozpoznanie, opisanie i skorelowanie występowania genetycznego polimorfizmów genu VDR, które pozwolą na wczesne rozpoznanie bądź zapobieganie wystąpienia skorelowanych z nimi jednostek chorobowych.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin D</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vitamin D receptor (VDR)</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osteoporosis</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymorphism</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>10</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>10</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>10</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30300431</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18544/PEDM-24.02.0108</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>