<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30273530</PMID>        <DateCompleted>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>11</Month>            <Day>16</Day>        </DateCompleted>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>11</Month>            <Day>16</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Electronic">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1853-0605</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>75</Volume>                    <Issue>2</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>06</Month>                        <Day>10</Day>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Revista de la Facultad de Ciencias Medicas (Cordoba, Argentina)</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Rev Fac Cien Med Univ Nac Cordoba</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[Laparoscopic Surgery for isolated lymph nodes recurrence in gynecology. Experience in Argentina.]</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>72-81</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.31053/1853.0605.v75.n2.17097</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText Label="Objectives">to describe the perioperative and oncological outcomes of a serie of cases treated with laparoscopic surgery for isolated nodal metastasis of gynecologic malignancies at the Gynecology Service of Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires and conduct a literature review on the surgical treatment provided to patients with this condition.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="Methods">A search was conducted in the surgery records of the Gynecology Service of Hospital Italiano of patients who underwent laparoscopic cytoreductive surgery for isolated nodal recurrence of a gynecologic primary tumor in the period 2009-2015. The medical records were reviewed and data on the patients’ characteristics, the tumor, the surgery and its complications were collected and analyzed. A literature search was conducted in Pubmed by the term “isolated nodal recurrence in gynecology” and a subsequent snowball search was performed.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="Results">As results, nine patients are presented. The median age was 66 years old (RI 7). The initial cancer location was: ovary (n=3), endometrium (n=3), cervix (n=2) and breast (n=1). The location site of the single nodal recurrence was the para-aortic area (n=8) and the pelvic area (n=1). The median of the disease-free interval to recurrence was 42.8 months (RI 40.2). Either the retroperitoneal or the transperitoneal approach was used based on the location of the recurrence. The median surgery time was 120 minutes (RI 36). No conversion to laparotomy was performed in any patient. No intraoperative or postoperative complications were reported, nor any requirement for blood transfusion. The median hospital stay was 36 hours. Adjuvant treatment with chemotherapy was applied to 8/9 patients. Only one patient recurred in para-aortic lymph nodes and peritoneal carcinomatosis after eight months and died of her disease. The literature review confirms the possibility of laparoscopic resection of the single nodal recurrence with low complication rate.</AbstractText>                <AbstractText Label="Conclusion">The laparoscopic lymph node cytoreductive surgery is a valid and safe treatment option considering the perioperative and oncological outcomes in our hospital.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Giavedoni</LastName>                    <ForeName>Maria Eugenia</ForeName>                    <Initials>ME</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires, Argentina. maria.giavedoni@hospitalitaliano.org.ar.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Saadi</LastName>                    <ForeName>Jose</ForeName>                    <Initials>J</Initials>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Saraniti</LastName>                    <ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName>                    <Initials>G</Initials>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Perrotta</LastName>                    <ForeName>Myriam</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>spa</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Citoreducción Ganglionar Laparoscópica en recidiva única por cánceres ginecológicos. Experiencia en Argentina.</VernacularTitle>            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>06</Month>                <Day>10</Day>            </ArticleDate>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Argentina</Country>            <MedlineTA>Rev Fac Cien Med Univ Nac Cordoba</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>8303003</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0014-6722</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>        <MeshHeadingList>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D001118" MajorTopicYN="N">Argentina</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D002277" MajorTopicYN="N">Carcinoma</DescriptorName>                <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="Y">surgery</QualifierName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D065426" MajorTopicYN="N">Cytoreduction Surgical Procedures</DescriptorName>                <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D018572" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease-Free Survival</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D005833" MajorTopicYN="N">Genital Neoplasms, Female</DescriptorName>                <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="Y">surgery</QualifierName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D010535" MajorTopicYN="N">Laparoscopy</DescriptorName>                <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D008197" MajorTopicYN="N">Lymph Node Excision</DescriptorName>                <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D059035" MajorTopicYN="N">Perioperative Period</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D012008" MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrence</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>            <MeshHeading>                <DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName>            </MeshHeading>        </MeshHeadingList>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">            <AbstractText Label="Objetivos">Describir los resultados perioperatorios y oncológicos de una serie de casos operados con laparoscopía por metástasis única ganglionar de cánceres ginecológicos en el Servicio de Ginecología del Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires y realizar una revisión bibliográfica sobre el tema.</AbstractText>            <AbstractText Label="Métodos">Se llevó a cabo una búsqueda de pacientes en los registros de cirugía del servicio de Ginecología del Hospital que hayan recibido tratamiento quirúrgico de citoreducción laparoscópica por recurrencia ganglionar aislada de un tumor primario ginecológico en el período 2009-2015. Se revisaron las historias clínicas y se recolectaron y analizaron datos referidos a características de las pacientes, del tumor, de la cirugía y sus complicaciones. Se realiza una búsqueda bibliográfica en Pubmed con el concepto &quot;isolated nodal recurrence in gynecology&quot; y posterior búsqueda en bola de nieve.</AbstractText>            <AbstractText Label="Resultados">Se presentan 9 pacientes. La mediana de edad fue de 66 años (RI 7). La localización del cáncer inicial fue ovario (n=3), endometrio (n=3), cuello (n=2) y mama (n=1). El sitio de localización de la recurrencia ganglionar única fue el área lumboaórtica (n=8) y el área pelviana (n=1). La mediana de intervalo libre de enfermedad a la recurrencia fue de 42.8 meses (RI 40.2). Se utilizó un abordaje retroperitoneal o transperitoneal según la localización de la recurrencia. La mediana de tiempo operatorio fue de 120 minutos (RI 36). No se realizó conversión a laparotomía en ninguna paciente. No se reportaron complicaciones intraoperatoria o postoperatorias, así como tampoco requerimiento de transfusión sanguínea. La mediana de estadía hospitalaria fue de 36 horas. Realizaron tratamiento adyuvante con quimioterapia 8/9 pacientes. Solo 1 paciente recurrió a nivel lumboaórtico y peritoneal luego de 8 meses y falleció de su enfermedad.La revisión de la literatura confirma la posibilidad de realizar la resección de la recurrencia ganglionar única por vía laparoscópica con baja tasa de complicaciones.</AbstractText>            <AbstractText Label="Conclusión">la citorreducción ganglionar laparoscópica es una opción de tratamiento válida y segura en relación a los resultados perioperatorios y oncológicos en nuestra institución.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">laparoscopy</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">isolated nodal recurrence</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">lymphadenectomy</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">gynecologic malignancy</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">                <Year>2017</Year>                <Month>06</Month>                <Day>02</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">                <Year>2017</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>10</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">                <Year>2017</Year>                <Month>09</Month>                <Day>20</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>2</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>10</Month>                <Day>3</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>11</Month>                <Day>18</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273530</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31053/1853.0605.v75.n2.17097</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>