<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30243716</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>10</Month>            <Day>12</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1090-2104</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>505</Volume>                    <Issue>1</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Oct</Month>                        <Day>20</Day>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Biochemical and biophysical research communications</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun.</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>Production and characterization of monoclonal antibody against a triple negative breast cancer cell line.</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>181-186</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0006-291X(18)32012-6</ELocationID>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bbrc.2018.09.087</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>Breast cancer is the most prevalent malignancy among women around the world such that more than 1,400,000 new cases are being diagnosed each year. Despite immense studies over many years on diagnosis and treatment of breast cancer, about 30% of treated patients will relapse and require subsequent therapy. By development of hybridoma technology, murine monoclonal antibodies (MAbs) against several human tumor-associated antigens have been produced and characterized in many laboratories. The purpose of these studies is to generate effective monoclonal antibodies that could be useful in tumor diagnosis and therapy. In this study, splenic lymphocytes of immunized BALB/c mouse with a new established breast cancer cell line (Pari-ICR cell line, established in Shiraz Institute for Cancer Research) were fused with the mouse myeloma cell line SP2/0 in the presence of polyethylene glycol. We generated a panel of monoclonal antibodies against the newly established cell line. The hybrid cultures were screened by flow cytometry. Hybridomas that produced antibody to surface antigens of immunizing cell line but not to Human Gingival Fibroblasts, adipose stem cells, and leucocytes isolated from peripheral blood were selected and cloned by limiting dilution method. The 1E3 clone (IgG2a type) that displayed clonal stability was further analyzed for specificity by flow cytometry. MAb 1E3 showed weak to strong reactivity to other cell lines compared with Pari-ICR cell line. Antigen identification was performed by a workflow consisting of immunoaffinity purification, SDS-PAGE, Western blotting, and mass spectrometry analysis. The target of 1E3 mAb was identified as NCAM1. In conclusion, using the antibody-based strategy we identified NCAM1 as a potential therapeutic target and biomarker for breast cancer.</AbstractText>                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2018 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Ghaderi</LastName>                    <ForeName>Farzaneh</ForeName>                    <Initials>F</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran; Shiraz Institute for Cancer Research, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. Electronic address: far.ghaderi@gmail.com.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Ahmadvand</LastName>                    <ForeName>Simin</ForeName>                    <Initials>S</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Shiraz Institute for Cancer Research, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. Electronic address: ahmadvand_s@sums.ac.ir.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Ramezani</LastName>                    <ForeName>Amin</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Shiraz Institute for Cancer Research, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran; Department of Medical Biotechnology, School of Advanced Medical Sciences and Technologies, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. Electronic address: aramezani@sums.ac.ir.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Montazer</LastName>                    <ForeName>Mehdi</ForeName>                    <Initials>M</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Fellow of Molecular Pathology and Cytogenetics, Department of Pathology, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. Electronic address: mehdi.montazer@gmail.com.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Ghaderi</LastName>                    <ForeName>Abbas</ForeName>                    <Initials>A</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Department of Immunology, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran; Shiraz Institute for Cancer Research, School of Medicine, Shiraz University of Medical Sciences, Shiraz, Iran. Electronic address: ghaderia@sums.ac.ir.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>eng</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>09</Month>                <Day>20</Day>            </ArticleDate>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>United States</Country>            <MedlineTA>Biochem Biophys Res Commun</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>0372516</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0006-291X</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarker</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword>            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Monoclonal antibody</Keyword>        </KeywordList>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>09</Month>                <Day>03</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>09</Month>                <Day>13</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>9</Month>                <Day>24</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>9</Month>                <Day>24</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>9</Month>                <Day>24</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30243716</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0006-291X(18)32012-6</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbrc.2018.09.087</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>