<?xml version="1.0" ?><!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st June 2018//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_180601.dtd"><PubmedArticleSet><PubmedArticle>    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Data-Review" Owner="NLM">        <PMID Version="1">30208185</PMID>        <DateRevised>            <Year>2018</Year>            <Month>09</Month>            <Day>12</Day>        </DateRevised>        <Article PubModel="Electronic">            <Journal>                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1678-4464</ISSN>                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">                    <Volume>34</Volume>                    <Issue>9</Issue>                    <PubDate>                        <Year>2018</Year>                        <Month>Sep</Month>                        <Day>06</Day>                    </PubDate>                </JournalIssue>                <Title>Cadernos de saude publica</Title>                <ISOAbbreviation>Cad Saude Publica</ISOAbbreviation>            </Journal>            <ArticleTitle>[Racial disparity in 10-year breast cancer survival: a mediation analysis using potential responses approach].</ArticleTitle>            <Pagination>                <MedlinePgn>e00211717</MedlinePgn>            </Pagination>            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0102-311X2018000905007</ELocationID>            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1590/0102-311X00211717</ELocationID>            <Abstract>                <AbstractText>The study's objectives were to investigate the association between race/color and 10-year survival in women with breast cancer and the role of staging as mediator. This was a hospital cohort with 481 women with invasive breast cancer diagnosed from 2003 to 2005. Comparisons were made between white and black women as to sociodemographic characteristics and staging, using the chi-square test, and 10-year survival, using Kaplan-Meier and Cox regression methods. For the race/color variable, direct and indirect effects were estimated, mediated by staging, with adjustment for the socioeconomic status of the woman's area of residence and age, using the potential responses (counterfactual) model and Cox multiple regression. Black women living in low-income census tracts were more likely to use the public health care system and to be diagnosed at more advanced stages. Breast cancer-specific 10-year survival was 64.3% (95%CI: 60.0; 68.9), with a significant difference between whites (69.5%; 95%CI: 64.8; 74.6) and blacks (44; 95%CI: 35.2%; 55.1). In the multivariate models adjusted for income and age, black women had worse prognosis (HR = 2.09; 95%CI: 1.76; 2.51), and the proportion mediated by staging was 40% (95%CI: 37; 42). There is racial disparity in 10-year breast cancer survival in Brazilian women, mediated mainly by more advanced staging at diagnosis in black women. This highlights the need to expand both the coverage and the quality of breast cancer screening and to facilitate access to early diagnosis and treatment in order to reduce racial inequality.</AbstractText>            </Abstract>            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Nogueira</LastName>                    <ForeName>Mário Círio</ForeName>                    <Initials>MC</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora, Brasil.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Guerra</LastName>                    <ForeName>Maximiliano Ribeiro</ForeName>                    <Initials>MR</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora, Brasil.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Cintra</LastName>                    <ForeName>Jane Rocha Duarte</ForeName>                    <Initials>JRD</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Instituto Oncológico, Juiz de Fora, Brasil.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Corrêa</LastName>                    <ForeName>Camila Soares Lima</ForeName>                    <Initials>CSL</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora, Brasil.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Fayer</LastName>                    <ForeName>Vívian Assis</ForeName>                    <Initials>VA</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora, Brasil.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>                <Author ValidYN="Y">                    <LastName>Bustamante-Teixeira</LastName>                    <ForeName>Maria Teresa</ForeName>                    <Initials>MT</Initials>                    <AffiliationInfo>                        <Affiliation>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade Federal de Juiz de Fora, Juiz de Fora, Brasil.</Affiliation>                    </AffiliationInfo>                </Author>            </AuthorList>            <Language>por</Language>            <PublicationTypeList>                <PublicationType UI="D004740">English Abstract</PublicationType>                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>            </PublicationTypeList>            <VernacularTitle>Disparidade racial na sobrevivência em 10 anos para o câncer de mama: uma análise de mediação usando abordagem de respostas potenciais.</VernacularTitle>            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>09</Month>                <Day>06</Day>            </ArticleDate>        </Article>        <MedlineJournalInfo>            <Country>Brazil</Country>            <MedlineTA>Cad Saude Publica</MedlineTA>            <NlmUniqueID>8901573</NlmUniqueID>            <ISSNLinking>0102-311X</ISSNLinking>        </MedlineJournalInfo>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="por">            <AbstractText>Os objetivos foram investigar a associação entre raça/cor e a sobrevivência em 10 anos de mulheres com câncer de mama e o papel do estadiamento como mediador. Coorte hospitalar com 481 mulheres com câncer invasivo de mama, diagnosticadas entre 2003 e 2005. Foram feitas comparações entre mulheres brancas e negras quanto às características sociodemográficas e ao estadiamento, usando o teste qui-quadrado, e à sobrevivência em 10 anos, usando os métodos de Kaplan-Meier e regressão de Cox. Foram estimados para a variável raça/cor efeitos diretos e indiretos, mediados pelo estadiamento, com ajuste para a condição social da área de residência e idade, utilizando o modelo de respostas potenciais (contrafactual) e regressão múltipla de Cox. As mulheres negras residiam em setores censitários de menor renda, eram usuárias do setor público em maior proporção e foram diagnosticadas com estadiamentos mais avançados. A sobrevivência específica em 10 anos foi de 64,3% (IC95%: 60,0; 68,9), com diferença significativa entre brancas (69,5%; IC95%: 64,8; 74,6) e negras (44%; IC95%: 35,2; 55,1). Nos modelos múltiplos, ajustados para renda e idade, as negras tiveram pior prognóstico (HR = 2,09; IC95%: 1,76; 2,51), e a proporção mediada pelo estadiamento foi de 40% (IC95%: 37; 42). Há disparidade racial na sobrevivência do câncer de mama em 10 anos, mediada principalmente pelo estadiamento mais avançado da doença nas mulheres negras. Isso aponta para a necessidade de ampliar a cobertura e a qualidade do programa de rastreamento dessa doença e facilitar o acesso ao diagnóstico e tratamento precoces, com vistas à redução da iniquidade racial.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>        <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">            <AbstractText>Los objetivos fueron investigar la asociación entre raza/color y la supervivencia en 10 años de mujeres con cáncer de mama y el papel de la fase de desarrollo como mediador. Se trata de una cohorte hospitalaria de 481 mujeres, con cáncer invasivo de mama, diagnosticadas entre 2003 y 2005. Se realizaron comparaciones entre mujeres blancas y negras, en cuanto a las características sociodemográficas y a la fase del cáncer, usando el test chi-quadrado, y la supervivencia en 10 años, usando los métodos de Kaplan-Meier y regresión de Cox. Se estimaron para la variable raza/color efectos directos e indirectos, mediados por las diferentes fases, con ajuste en la condición social del área de residencia y edad, utilizando el modelo de respuestas potenciales (contrafactual) y regresión múltiple de Cox. Las mujeres negras residían en sectores censitarios de menor renta, eran usuarias del sector público en mayor proporción y fueron diagnosticadas en fases más avanzadas. La supervivencia específica en 10 años fue de un 64,3% (IC95%: 60,0; 68,9), con una diferencia significativa entre blancas (69,5%; IC95%: 64,8%-74,6%) y negras (44%; IC95%: 35,2; 55,1). En los modelos múltiples, ajustados para renta y edad, las negras tuvieron un peor pronóstico (HR = 2,09; IC95%: 1,76-2,51), y la proporción mediada por el estadio fue de un 40% (IC95%: 37; 42). Existe disparidad racial en la supervivencia del cáncer de mama en 10 años, mediada principalmente por el estadio más avanzado de la enfermedad en las mujeres negras. Esto apunta la necesidad de ampliar la cobertura y calidad del programa de rastreo de esa enfermedad y facilitar el acceso al diagnóstico y tratamiento precoces, con vistas a la reducción de la inequidad racial.</AbstractText>        </OtherAbstract>    </MedlineCitation>    <PubmedData>        <History>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">                <Year>2017</Year>                <Month>12</Month>                <Day>06</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>05</Month>                <Day>02</Day>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>9</Month>                <Day>13</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>9</Month>                <Day>13</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">                <Year>2018</Year>                <Month>9</Month>                <Day>13</Day>                <Hour>6</Hour>                <Minute>0</Minute>            </PubMedPubDate>        </History>        <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>        <ArticleIdList>            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30208185</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0102-311X2018000905007</ArticleId>            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0102-311X00211717</ArticleId>        </ArticleIdList>    </PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>